# SALMA NEGM

## MARKETING MANAGER

### CONTACT

- 0566447828
- ✓ salnegm24@gmail.com
- Dubai, UAE

## SUMMARY

An enthusiastic brand marketing manager with over 7 years of experience in a wide range of industries including fashion & technology. I have a passion for cultural storytelling, and have successfully completed many projects to amplify and provide creative and innovative solutions for brands in the Middle East.

### EDUCATION

#### **MBA**

WARWICK BUSINESS SCHOOL MAY 2022- MAY 2024

BSC BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF SHARJAH SEPTEMBER 2013- MAY 2017 GPA: 3.51

### EXPERIENCE

## REGIONAL PARTNER MARKETING MANAGER SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS

#### JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

- Managed and executed partner marketing campaigns for premium smartphones by fostering strong internal and external relationships.
- Conducted insightful data analysis, presenting key findings and actionable insights to the MENA executive team, contributing to the strategic direction and optimization of partnerships.
- Ensured meticulous strategy, execution and audit of partnership campaigns across diverse channels, including OOH, TV, digital, and retail, enhancing brand visibility and impact in MENA markets.
- Developed partner marketing budget for 8 subsidiaries, splitting it effectively across key touchpoints.
- Created quarterly playbooks for subsidiaries with strategy on campaign planning, execution and competitor benchmarking.

## REGIONAL BRAND ACTIVATION AND DIGITAL SPECIALIST ADIDAS

#### **FEBRUARY 2020 - JUNE 2022**

- Developed and implemented comprehensive marketing strategies, aligning with regional brand objectives and business goals.
- Briefed and aligned all channels on 360 campaign plans, to collaborate on regular insights and develop methods to drive traffic to retail and e-commerce partners.
- Created thorough data-driven campaign planning and reporting files to track performance of marketing activities and explore learnings.
- Fostered robust partnerships with various stakeholders, including franchise, wholesale accounts, and online pure players.
- Led effective in-store and consumer activation strategies, enhancing brand presence and engagement in the region.
- Developed a PR and influencer strategy for each campaign, working closely with key influencers, across categories, to drive campaign engagement and conversion activity.
- Collaborated with various agencies to develop detailed campaign plans and execution.
- Managed the marketing working budget effectively, ensuring optimal allocation and utilization of funds.

## LANGUAGES

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Powerpoint

Microsoft Word

Microsoft Outlook

Adobe Photoshop

Google Adwords

Google Analytics

## OTHER SKILLS

**Collaborative Team Player** 

**Driven to Deliver** 

Self- Starter Attitude

**Analytical and Critical Thinker** 

**Detail Oriented** 

**Confident Public Speaker** 

**Highly Organized** 

**Effective Negotiator** 

**Commercially Aware** 

**Fast Paced** 

## FIELD AND TRADE MARKETING SPECIALIST ADIDAS

#### FEBRUARY 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

- Executed creative brand activations in prominent wholesale fashion accounts within the GCC region, enhancing in-store sales and brand visibility.
- Owned and managed end-to-end fashion projects, from briefing to execution, aligning with budget constraints and ensuring successful outcomes.
- Engaged fashion customers through captivating in-store launches, encouraging customer co-creation and effectively showcasing brand narratives.
- Developed PR strategy for key hype and fashion launches, ensuring creative storytelling through end to end campaign planning and execution,

## MARKETING SPECIALIST- FASHION & F&B AZADEA

#### FEBRUARY 2018- FEBRUARY 2019

- Successfully managed and allocated a substantial marketing budget across various brands, focusing on key touch-points like social media and digital marketing.
- Initiated and implemented critical projects for notable fashion brands, ensuring effective and collaborative execution with team members.
- Engaged and partnered with influencers from diverse niches, including sports, food, lifestyle, and fashion, maximizing their reach and impact for various projects.
- Worked with a variety of agencies, ranging from PR to activation, to have seamless project execution and gain exceptional insights from the market.

## MARKETING EXECUTIVE UNILEVER JULY 2017 - FEBRUARY 2018

- Launched the "Happier Workplace by Lipton" initiative successfully in the UAE, collaboratively working with a team and establishing partnerships with the UAE Ministry of State for Happiness.
- Conducted detailed customer insight analysis, utilizing both qualitative and quantitative data from surveys and focus groups to inform decision-making processes.
- Implemented data analysis techniques to identify and address underperforming products, contributing innovative solutions and proposals for improvement.
- Assisted in the introduction of the Unilever Food Solutions' ecommerce platform, collaborating efficiently with sales and commercial departments to ensure a smooth launch.
- Played a crucial role in the Hellmann's mayonnaise re-launch in the UAE, leading a significant brand awareness campaign and supporting brand positioning in the market.